<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ruby | House of Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-27T09:04:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew House]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewhouse621@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homework App]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/18/homework-app/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-18T15:40:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/18/homework-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I built an app which some of my fellow students can use as a medium to give
progress on their homework assignments.<br>
<a href="http://tiy-homework.herokuapp.com">My App</a> uses Devise for registering users,
Heroku as the means for depoloyment, and a vast array of fun gems.
The whole point of the app is that there is a central place where our teacher
(James Dabbs) can check our homework progress.
James is the only authorized user (admin) capable of making new assignments.
Then each student can update the status of their homework by selecting a created
assignment, post the link of their website, and check to see if the assignment
has been completed.<br><br>
I think it works pretty well, all of the CSS was done with the help of
<a href="http://getbootstrap.com/">Twitter Bootstrap</a>. If you are interested in
checking out my code, I have it posted on <a href="https://github.com/andrewhouse/TIY-Homework-Checker">Github</a>.
<br>
But yea, making apps are fun. I had a lot of challenges in this app.
Something different I did in this that I had never done before was implementing
a has_many_through relationship.
It required me to do quite a bit of reading to see how each piece interacted,
but in the end it was totally worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gem Choices]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/13/gem-choices/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T16:37:02-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/13/gem-choices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gem&rsquo;s make my Rails world go round. <br>
However, there are so many gems around that it would take entirely too long
to comb through them all.
I do have a method that helps me select certain gems from others. <br>
<strong>Documentation.</strong><br>
If a gem is lacking in how-to&rsquo;s, tutorials, or efficient documentation-I
typically skip over it.
For example, one of my favorite gems is <a href="https://github.com/plataformatec/simple_form">Simple Form</a>.
Simple Form allows forms to be a little easier to read.
My favorite part about it?<br>
Look at all of that documenation on the Github page.<br>
I love it.
There have been situations where I use gems that don&rsquo;t have great documentation.
Typically that is when I&rsquo;m desperate for something and have exhausted my resources.
Odds are, the gem is a failure and I crawl into a little hole for a few minutes.
Alas, gems are great to use and their documentation/codebase allows for steady
knowledge and easy implementation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sinatra Is Fun]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/11/sinatra-is-fun/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-11T21:09:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/11/sinatra-is-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I never really gave Sinatra a chance. <br>
After reading articles after articles about how much better Rails is than
Sinatra, I kind of swept it under the rug.
I was sooooo wrong. <br>
Sinatra is crazy light weight.
Not as many bells, whistles, and not near as many headaches that come with Rails.
It&rsquo;s simplistic, and I like that.
Today I built <a href="http://andrew-sinatra.herokuapp.com/" title="Andrew House - Sinatra">a fun Sinatra app</a>
and I had a really great time.
I didn&rsquo;t try to make it too complicated, just trying to get used to haml and
getting into the groove of how sinatra should feel.<br><br>
I enjoyed how some of the magic that you take for granted in Rails is peeled
apart in Sinatra.
Making my own get/post requests and assigning routes was fun.
I may be overplaying it, and I know how beneficial rails will be when I take
on a larger app. But I have to say that now I will turn to sinatra for low
level simplistic apps. Kudos to James for making us play with Sinatra.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting Over]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/08/starting-over/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-08T23:37:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/08/starting-over</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I LOVE to play around with new features. <br>
Tonight I was playing around with omniauth-github and trying to log in via rails.
I was able to log in (horray!), but I had forgotten what I was supposed to be
doing initially.
It happens to me every now and then; I get feature focused. <br><br>
I&rsquo;m so focused on getting this one little thing to work I lose track of
my goal. It&rsquo;s times like this, when I&rsquo;m barely into the project, and I was
able to get my feature to work.
I find that it&rsquo;s best to scrap it and start over.
My reasoning?<br>
  <li>Start on a path where I am able to remain focused.
  <li>When it is time to create the feature again; I will do it again from scratch,
forcing myself to learn.
  <li>In future projects, I will know to be well prepared and focused from the get go.
<br><br>
Long story short. <br>
I played around with a cool thing, got it to work, messed up, started over, and
didn&rsquo;t loose any passion.
Not a bad thing if you ask me.
I&rsquo;ll learn, grow, and do a better job next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Ruby Chose Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/06/how-ruby-chose-me/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-06T08:49:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/06/how-ruby-chose-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Javascript was my first programming language.
While it was fun to use, it was also very syntax heavy.
The amount of ()&rsquo;s and {}&rsquo;s pretty much drove me insane.  <br>
After learning the basics of Javascript I started to look for other
languages that would be relevant to my goal of web development.
I had come to learn how Javascript was incredibly important making web
pages function, and I wanted to learn the skills to drive the essential
pieces that run in the background. That&rsquo;s right, I wanted to take a look
into the back-end. <br></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>After researching for countless days I finally stumbled upon Ruby on Rails.
It seemed that Rails was a great way to start looking into the backend.
However, the majority of places I saw said to absolutly not start Rails
until I was fluent in Ruby.
Then a lightbulb moment came.
I remember seeing a Ruby course when I was going over the Javascript codeacademy
course.
There I went, headfirst into Ruby without a clue of what it was.<br><br>
I thought Ruby was joking with me.
Hardly any ()&rsquo;s and only {}&rsquo;s with hashes and blocks. Are you serious?
It was fluid, less verbose, and object oriented.
I fell head over heels.
From that point on I focused mainly on Ruby and learning how to properly structure
methods, classes, and everything I could.
I&rsquo;ve got to the point to where just getting something to work the way I want to isn&rsquo;t
enought, I need to have it be in best practice.
Using proper standards and conventions adopted by professionals.
Ruby is a ton of fun.
I&rsquo;m incredibly passionate about it and it has made me a more passionate developer.<br><br>
Ruby pulled me into it&rsquo;s world and I couldn&rsquo;t be happier.
From there I went to learn basic Rails and make a few web apps of my own.
Currently, I am attending the IronYard in Atlanta, GA to learn more
advanced Ruby and Rails.
By the end of this I feel I will be absolutely be prepared to be a critical
asset to any team. <br><br>
I have Ruby to thank for all of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
