<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hackathon | House of Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/categories/hackathon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-18T09:19:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew House]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewhouse621@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[After: The Iron Yard Hackathon]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/07/after-the-iron-yard-hackathon/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-07T21:44:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/07/after-the-iron-yard-hackathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That was intense.<br>
I had a really fun time this weekend.
It&rsquo;s amazing how much can be accomplished in such a short amount of time.
I went into the hackathon with the mindset of building something that would work when it was over.
I was successful.<br><br>
Our app was a pseudo dropbox that would be used by businesses and allow clients to
download/upload files without making an account.
I took the task of scrumming together a work flow for my team for the weekend,
gathering input from a couple of the pitchers.
Because of this, we never had a situation where we asked what was next.
At the end, I was told that I looked and acted like a project manager.
 Also, our app looked like an enterprise worthy application,
and was planned and built accordingly.
That was a pretty nice ego boost, to get feedback from strangers that my
techniques in building and managing and application are very effective.<br><br>
Working with a front end developer and an IOS developer was very fun.
Being able to cultivate my data to tailor their needs was different.
Our front end developer was very fresh to The Iron Yard (2 weeks in)
and was a stellar developer.
I took the time Saturday to teach him Haml and he took to it quickly(major props to you Dean).
Being on a team like that was worth the whole weekend to me.
To be around minds who also had a thirst for knowldge and had a different perspective on everything.
I look at things very logically, they had a much better perspective on design and user expereience.
I had a great team and more importantly had an absolute blast.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Before: The Iron Yard Hackathon]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/03/before-the-iron-yard-hackathon/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-03T17:37:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/03/before-the-iron-yard-hackathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So in about 20 minutes the internal hackathon at The Iron Yard Atlanta is going to begin. <br>
I&rsquo;m pretty pumped.<br>
Not really knowing what I&rsquo;m going to be building.<br>
Who I&rsquo;m going to be working with.<br>
If I&rsquo;ll be able to do everything I want to in the time frame (probably not).<br>
All of these variables seem like it&rsquo;s going to bring an epic weekend.<br><br>
The teams are going to be preselected.
Each team will get at least one Rails Engineer, IOS Developer, and Front End Developer.
Most teams will be groups of 3, some groups of 4.
I&rsquo;m hoping to think that my team is going to be extraordinarily bad ass.
Well to be perfectly honest, everyone at The Iron Yard has talent.
Everyone will be able to contribute something.
I know going into it that I want my team to scrum our project.
I already have a nice spreadsheet laid out and ready to go.
Now it&rsquo;s only a matter of time before we start.<br><br>
I&rsquo;m excited.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forge Hackathon]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/25/forge-hackathon/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-25T10:27:33-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/25/forge-hackathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was a mentor at my first hackathon.<br>
Weird right?
The Iron Yard was a sponsor at the <a href="http://forgeatl.com/">Forge Hackathon</a> in Atlanta,
and they asked their students if some of them would like to be mentors.
I thought it would be a great experience to see what a hackathon&rsquo;s atmosphere
is like, and talk to people and see what they&rsquo;re thinking.
So I roll in Saturday morning and sit in a room just for software development.
My role as a mentor was to sit and wait for people to ask for help.
After about 5 minutes of sitting, I was approached by a team looking for help.<br><br>
Their idea was that they were developing a wearable band that doctors were
able to update their personal data.
Such as basic information (name, birthday, etc) and more elaborate data such
as diseases, medication, etc.
The problem they had was that their target locations only had internet once every
few months and didn&rsquo;t know how to store their data locally.
I recommended storing basic data on the wristband (before they were only trying
to store the data on a server with a wristband having only an id).
This way, when the doctor has internet they can push their data up to the server,
allowing the internet copy to be up to date.
The copy on the wristband would be as current as the doctor&rsquo;s version is.
So if they were to move and go to a different doctor, that doctor would
have the most up to date version that their previous doctor had.<br>
Then afterwards I explained strategies to span out their data model into
separate categories to help future expansion and allow for easier transitions
of adding data.
For example, <br>
instead of having a single User table, break medication, doctors, &amp; diseases
into a separate table so that adding and removing data would be much more
efficient. <br><br>
All in all, they seemed to really enjoy my feedback (actually, I asked if
I was helpful and they said I was a huge help).
My first hackathon experience was pretty awesome, it helped my resolve in
believing in myself and trusting the knowledge I have to help others.
It&rsquo;s a spectacular feeling.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
