<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Css | House of Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/categories/css/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-25T09:08:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew House]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewhouse621@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing a Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/08/designing-a-website/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-08T17:13:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/08/designing-a-website</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An eye for art I do not have. <br>
I can&rsquo;t paint, draw, sculpt or any of the like.
When it comes to making things look good, I have to say that I am a numskull.
However, I think designing a website is incredibly challenging and somehow fun.
I&rsquo;m not very fluent in css.
I can read it just fine, but when it comes to creating my own css from my own ideas,
I find it hard.
I tend to use tools like Twitter Bootstrap, ones that can give a default layout
and style without me having to give it much thought.
After a talk today with Sam Kapila, I felt a little at ease when thinking about
web design.
<br><br>
It&rsquo;s all about the User Experience. <br>
Making the person who is going to read my page to feel comfortable.
Not having to search for what they need, making it very clear, and using tools/tricks
to have a much easier reading experience.
For example, something as simple as not having the lines of text too close together.
I typically don&rsquo;t think about things like that.
I have a very backend oriented brain.
I just needed to use my perspective to design. <br>
Then I had a lightbulb moment.<br>
Pay attention to certain details on websites that annoy me and don&rsquo;t do that(also the opposite).
It&rsquo;s simple.
Do I hate that color? DON&rsquo;T DO IT. Do I like the way that navigation is laid out?
Inspect that element and see what they did.
I believe I&rsquo;m making designing harder than it is.
I just have to KISS (Keep It Simple Stupid) it a little.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
