<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Ironyard | House of Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/categories/the-ironyard/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-18T09:19:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew House]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewhouse621@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demo Day: Aftershock]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/18/demo-day-aftershock/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-18T08:56:17-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/18/demo-day-aftershock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came, I saw, and it was awesome.<br>
All of my fellow Rails classmates did amazing.
It was so much fun watching everyone go up and present their final projects.
Not a single person lacked passion and love for their project.
I have a lot of pride in my project, <a href="http://pricetimate.com">Pricimate</a>.<br><br>
The idea for my project came from my wife.
She&rsquo;s in touch with the artistic community and knew that there was a void for new artists.<br>
They don&rsquo;t know how to price their works of art for sell.<br>
So I made that my mission. <strong>Help Artists Price Their Work</strong>
I proceeded to scrum out what my wife/client believed to be important, calculated my story points for each, and found my priority list.<br>
For MVP, I got all of my basic features working in Rails.
But that wasn&rsquo;t good enough, I needed more dynamic features, so I proceeded to work in AngularJS.
In the end, my app worked exactly how I wanted it to.
<br><br>
I practiced my presentation many, many, many times.
Being 100% prepared was essential for me.
Stumbling, forgetting where I was, or skipping a few sentences were not things I was going to do.<br>
And I nailed it.<br>
We had 6 minutes alloted for presentations; Mine was 5:57 (we had a timer on our podium).
I felt like I had complete confidence in my app because I prepared as much as I did.
People had engaging questions after my presenations, like what I had to offer was very interesting to them.
More importantly, in intermission I had three people come up and directly compliment my app, offer their direct feedback(which was great) and wanted to know my current employment status.<br>
I was floating.<br><br>
I had so much fun at The Iron Yard.<br>
Would definitely recommend it to anyone who wanted to learn an insane amount of content in a short amount of time.
It requires dedication. You will get out what you put into it.
Being satisfied by getting the work done isn&rsquo;t enough.
You have to push yourself and take what is given and throw it up a couple of levels.<br>
Don&rsquo;t like the page having refresh over and over? Use Ajax, or something like AngularJS.<br>
The beginning Ruby assignments seem easy to you? Write tests for them, or throw up your work on sinatra. <br>
There are countless things to do to push learning to the absolute maximum, and it all falls on your dedication.
I loved every bit of being there, I don&rsquo;t regret a day I spent at The Iron Yard.
I feel 100% confident I can solve many complex problems I don&rsquo;t have the answer to, and that is because of my training.
Now the job hunt begins, and I don&rsquo;t feel like it&rsquo;ll be too stressful because of how much weight the name &ldquo;The Iron Yard&rdquo; holds.
<br>
Life is pretty great when you push yourself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Day Before Demo Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/16/the-day-before-demo-day/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-16T08:23:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/16/the-day-before-demo-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I woke up surprisingly energetic this morning.<br>
I think it is because I feel prepared and excited to give my demo.
The amount of work that has gone into my final project at The Iron Yard has been intense.
The last two weeks I&rsquo;ve worked mostly 10+ hours a day sorting out everything I wanted.
Starting by building an app from scratch, to a finished/polished product that is in working condition.
That was one thing that I wanted from my final project.
Not an app that had hard coded information, or tweaked just for our presentation.
But a real, live, working application that can be used with minimal difficulty.<br><br>
I have had a ridiculous amount of fun these last couple of weeks.
Digging into code, building something that was entirely based on my skill, and being able to show it off to others.
I feel like I&rsquo;m on cloud 9.
It&rsquo;s really a great thing that I scrum&rsquo;d out my workflow as to set specific goals in a timely manner.
I would be freaking out if I still had to work on code today.
It has been stressful, meeting personal deadlines, not knowing how the end product will turn out.
I feel confident now.
My work is great and it is an uplifting feeling to create something by yourself that is a presentable product.
<br><br>
My next post will detail the application that I built.
I&rsquo;ll go over why I built it and for who.
Also I&rsquo;ll post the link for the app and my github.
<br><br>
Many thanks to the folks at The Iron Yard.
It&rsquo;s been a blast.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/13/final-week/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T07:52:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/10/13/final-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is my last week at The Iron Yard.<br>
It feels like the last 11 weeks have flown by, mainly because I have been having a ridiculous amount of fun.
I have been stressed, anxious, and nervous.
Learning how to cope with all is part of being a developer.
To take the negative feelings and look beyond them.
<br>&ldquo;Why am I feeling stressed? I guess it&rsquo;s because I&rsquo;m having a hard time getting this to work.&rdquo;<br>
Understanding yourself and the root of your feelings can be a driving force.
After understanding the stress, I can redirect it into a thirst for knowledge.<br>
<br>
I&rsquo;ll be happy and sad after my demo day is done.
Happy that I had completed the course to the best of my abilities, learning so many different things.
Sad that the environment that I have been in, everyone giving 100% to learn, will be over.
But alas!
A new chapter will start, with great people with great purposes.
Life is pretty cool if you give it a chance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
