<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Work | House of Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-03T17:46:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew House]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewhouse621@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for My Final Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/09/25/preparing-for-my-final-project/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-25T08:38:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/09/25/preparing-for-my-final-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s about to get crazy at The Iron Yard.<br>
We have a week and a half of lecture and practice until we begin final projects.
Honestly, I have no idea what I&rsquo;m going to do.
I know that I would love to build a site combining the strengths of Rails backend with Angular JS&rsquo;s front end.
I suck at ideas though.
If I have an idea of what to build, the general idea, then I can run with it and do something fun.
Getting that initial idea is hard as hell for me.
I plan on asking various people to get their advise for what kind of project would be memorable and useable.
From October 3-5 The Iron Yard is doing an internal hackathon (Combination of the Front End, IOS, and Rails classes) and I hope that I get an idea from there that I can run with for my final project.
I would love to work with other classes and form a Scrum centric idea process and work flow to knock down a project.<br> <br>
The last couple of weeks have been group projects for us.
Last week I was the project leader of our group and it was very different experience for me.
I didn&rsquo;t do pure scrum with the group.
I didn&rsquo;t get client input, or make a board.
I kind of winged the inputs in my head to develop a MVP.
This week the leader of our group was a former project manager, <a href="https://github.com/rjgroller">Robert Groller</a>, and knows how to use scrum.
Actual scrum implementation is much different than &ldquo;winging it&rdquo;.
I like the workflow process much better with full scrum.
The timeboxing, workflow, and everything.
I want this process in my final project.
My intention is to have James, my teacher, act as the client and give me feedback on what he thinks a user experience should find important in whatever I do. <br><br>
Now I just need to figure out what I&rsquo;m going to do.
I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ll figure it out soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enforcing Knowledge]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/09/08/enforcing-knowledge/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-08T14:15:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/09/08/enforcing-knowledge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We go through material so fast at The Iron Yard.<br>
It isn&rsquo;t like we go through things too fast, but just fast enough
to understand everything.
I personally have a tendency to forget basic syntax when blazing through
new material.<br>
Do I put a semi-colon here or wrap it in quotation marks?<br>
Do I need curly brackets here?<br>
Little details like that come up often in my brain.
I find it helpful to try to not remember the exact syntax, but where
I wrote code similar to that to reference.
That way I&rsquo;m not trying to rush and memorize specific syntax, but
over time as I continuously refer to my own work it will become
more normal.<br><br>
Personally, I enjoy looking at code that I have wrote before.
Especially code that I don&rsquo;t remember.
I can see my progress and have the &ldquo;what was I thinking when I wrote this?&rdquo;
moments.
To be able to mock my previous self is crucial in self evolution.
See what I did, and make it better.
Then I&rsquo;m not just referencing some article online, but take something
that I put time into and make a new reference by upgrading it.
There is always something to do.
Code can always be smaller, faster, and more efficient.
It&rsquo;s my job to find a perfect balance between those and the time it takes
to write the code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking the Norm]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/09/02/breaking-the-norm/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-02T21:23:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/09/02/breaking-the-norm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been living in a state of being uncomfortable.<br>
It&rsquo;s a weird feeling.
Always having to look up resources, reading articles, and watching videos.<br>
It is constant learning.<br>
At first, this style was incredibly uneasy.
I would feel constantly anxious and stressed.
Why didn&rsquo;t I have the answers?
Why was I having such a hard time finding answers?
There is a great skill in asking the right questions, and a very valuable lesson
I learned.
I think my next blog post will be how to google 101, or googling for rails dummies.
The evolution of my ability to see through what problem I am facing and
being able to search for that specific problem has been astonishing.
I&rsquo;m starting to transition from being uneasy all the time to enjoying the hunt.<br><br>
Where are the answers?<br>
Which answer is the best for my needs?<br>
Can I tweak the answer to get better results?<br><br>
I feel like this is a great mentality to have.
To be always improving is what it takes to be a developer.
Breaking my old ways of doing what it is easy, digging into the trenches,
and putting some sweat equity into me.
It&rsquo;s a pretty rewarding feeling.
Looking at myself from the outside in and noticing a change.
I am so glad that I am coding.
It truly was a life altering choice to come to The Iron Yard.
Not only will I become a badass Rails Dev, but I will also be closer to
my true self.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Electric]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/its-electric/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-07T20:41:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/its-electric</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Electricity sure is annoying.<br>
I end up using it most of the day.
Whether it be by charging my laptop, heating up dinner, or watching tv.
Electricity encompasses my life.<br>
I&rsquo;m not saying I don&rsquo;t particularly like it, I just hate being dependent on
factors I can&rsquo;t control.
Currently the power is out at my apartment and I find it incredibly frustrating.
The thought of how we will use power in the future gives me great joy.
Affordable personal solar panels that are easy to diagnose? Yes please.
I&rsquo;d even take a Soylent Green-esque treadmill that could power my apartment.<br><br>
I know that I&rsquo;m overly dependent on electricity; my profession pretty much relies on it.
If something happened and we went back to the stone age, I would be royally screwed.
I do enjoy the era I was born into, and I look forward to the future and what
humanity will come up with to fill the void for everyone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
