<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Object Oriented Programming | House of Rails]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/categories/object-oriented-programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-08T23:45:21-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew House]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrewhouse621@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Object Oriented]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/being-object-oriented/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-07T10:02:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewhouse.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/being-object-oriented</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love designing classes in an Object Oriented fashion.
It gives a good feeling, like there aren&rsquo;t just a bunch of empty method.
Each method belongs to something larger, each piece makes the whole complete.
Object Oriented Programming (OOP) just makes sense to me.<!-- more --> <br><br>
I like to think of classes as factories.
Each factory pumps out a special part thats essential for the whole.
The combination of all of the parts produced by the factories make a larger
object.
Attacking problems this way helps me pre-debug(defensive coding) the situation.
Doing so makes it easier to debug, read, and understand.
<br><br>
Even when not specifically designing Object Oriented features, I still
think of designing projects like objects.
Let&rsquo;s say I&rsquo;m building a rails app.
At the top level there is the MVC(model, view, controller).
From there I break it down into pieces.
Each view has several HTML &amp; CSS files.
Each HTML can have partials, their own css stylings, etc.
I keep breaking every piece down and down to make every little bit easier to
understand.
To me, designing this way helps maintain my sanity and keep organized.<br></p>

<p>Objects are my friends, and designing in such a way isn&rsquo;t too hard of a task.
Just be mindful of the roles each object plays, name them accordingly, and
create the puzzle that holds all the pieces perfectly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
